place to play football. The atmosphere
that's created through DQ um is one that
I love being a part of and there was to
me um no doubt in my mind that I wanted
to be back and nothing really knocked my
socks off. So this is where I wanted to
be and I'm privileged and blessed to be
back.
>> And then there's a change in
coordinators and and obviously Cliff is
out. You love that offense. What about
David Blau? What what do you think about
that change and was that was that any
you know how much did you consider that
in paying your options.
>> Well, from the first time I met Blau,
like you could tell how smart he was and
just an unbelievable um person. Like he
not only would he just drive our entire
quarterback room with competition and
all that kind of stuff, but like he was
adamant day in and day out of providing
whatever we needed, um trying to make us
the best version of ourselves. And when
you build a relationship with somebody
like that, um it you can't help but just
try to be a part of it. And I'm excited
to see what this all looks like. Um I
think Blau is a perfect fit for this. Um
it is an incredible situation to walk
into. Um but I think through his
experiences and all that he's been
through, there's no better person for
this job.
>> JP
>> Marcus, congratulations, man. Um
>> thank you. You just finished a workout
looking
>> Yeah. [laughter]
>> I love it. I love it.
>> I'm I'm curious
as much as you talked about DQ being
there and Blau being there from, you
know, since you joined here, there there
is obviously a lot of continuity, but
there's also a lot of differences now.
How does that feel going forward?
>> Yeah, you know what? It's kind of
similar to when I first got here. Um,
and the importance of creating a healthy
quarterback room is really our our
standard. Um, and again, like I said,
quarterback rooms across the league
aren't like this. Um, not everybody in
there is close. Not everybody wants to
see the guy who's playing play well, and
I I didn't want to pass that up. Um, so
for us, the continuity in that room is
important um, amongst the players. And
really when it comes down to it, Blau's
been through all of that with us. Um,
he's seen how great it can be, he can
also see like when things are hard and
tough. And I think all those challenges,
all those experiences will only make
this room better. And when it comes down
to it, the health is and the m the
mindset of this quarterback room is the
most important thing in the entire
building.
And then knowing the offense is going to
change both for you and Jaden, similar
players. Like how different do things
look for you if you're under center that
much more, if you're running, you know,
true traditional play action and
bootlegs that much more?
>> Well, I you know, I've been fortunate to
kind of be in a lot of different
systems. So, early on in my career, I've
been in systems like this where um you
know, we are under center, we are asked
to do those types of things. Um is that
what we're going to do? I don't think
necessarily what we don't really know
what it all looks like just yet. Um, and
I think what's cool for us is we're
going to get to experience a lot of
different things to see what we do best
and Blau's going to kind of implement it
that way. Um, because really what it
comes down to is you can have all the
different shotgun, pistol, under center.
Um, but it really matters in how we're
operating. And I think what will be fun
in this off season, these OTAAS is being
being stimulated, doing different
things, challenges, and I think
eventually we'll find what's best for
all of us, and it'll be created to
tailor whoever is in there. And um I'm
excited to be a part of that process.
>> Thanks, D. Congrats again.
>> Thank you so much. Good to see you.
>> David Harrison.
>> Hey, Marcus. Good to see you.
Congratulations.
>> Thank you, Dave. Um, I want to ask you
as a free agent when you're, you know,
going through this process of of
identifying what team you're going to
stay with or or join, money is obviously
a part of it, but how much is everything
else you're talking about? Culture and
fit and relationships.
>> Those are important. Those are
priorities. Um, you know, I I we always
kind of as a family, we look at like
what's the most important things uh as
we head into free agency. Um, you know,
for the last few years it's it's been
location. you know, we've wanted to go
back west uh to be completely
transparent. Um but that falls below
culture and system and those types of
things. Um so for me, regardless of
wherever it is, having the opportunity
to be in a culture and in an offensive
system where it feels like it's going to
be catered and allow me to be the best
version of myself, that's most
important. Um everything else is a
bonus. and um you know to be in a great
quarterback room like this to be around
Blau and to see this system come to life
um was a challenge and a and uh
opportunity that I didn't want to pass
up.
>> And then obviously you you've been able
to go through multiple system changes
and coaching changes through your career
as a veteran. How big of an undertaking
are those changes for a quarterback?
>> Yeah, it's a process and it's going to
take some time. Um I think everyone
always expects it to be good right away.
Um, but we always have to kind of look
back and understand that it is a
journey. Um, and we're all going to
figure this out together. Um, we
understand like what we've done well,
what we need to improve on. Um, and so
we get to kind of start clean and build
off of the the all the great things and
find ways to improve on some of the
weaker things. Um, so I think that for
me was was a interesting and new
challenge. Um, and I I'm excited to to
be a part of it. And like I said, the
end of the day, it's it's going to be
tailored to however we can be best as an
offense. Um, and I really believe in
that and Blau's going to be the best at
that.
>> Thanks, Marcus.
>> Thank you,
>> Candy.
>> Hey, Marcus. Good morning again.
>> Good morning. Good morning.
>> Welcome back.
>> Thank you.
>> Um, so for you last year and you know,
you've been in the league for a while.
you've you've experienced a lot, but so
what did you learn new about yourself
the last season?
>> Yeah, I learned um a lot about just
being a leader and how to continue to
relate to guys, how to continue to
motivate guys, especially when things
aren't going great. Um I felt like I
learned a lot about that early on in my
career. Um so it it really kind of tests
me last season. And when it comes down
to it, when guys want to play for each
other, um the attitude and the effort
won't change. And I thought that was
definitely a focal point at the end of
the year. You know, guys could have
easily just been like, "All right, we're
good. We're kind of moving on." But guys
played hard and the effort, the drive,
the determination to win was always
there. Um so that just solidified to me
how great of a culture and atmosphere
there is here. And the end of the day,
like we're always going to find ways to
improve. That's what I love about this
game. I'm always chasing the best
version of myself and I really believe
that this type of atmosphere and this
culture can really allow me to do that.
>> And in all's kind of first year together
back in 2024, I think towards the end of
the year, everyone started to really see
publicly the relationship that you built
with Jaden in the entire quarterback
room. So again, going back to last
season, what did you learn about Jaden
and the adversity that he faced last
season?
>> Well, we talked about it. Every great
quarterback has to go through it. has to
have the adversity. I think it just like
creates that foundation for them to
really springboard and that was Jay's
moment. That was kind of his undertaking
and for all of us to be there to support
him through that um was important and
again like I said it was a privilege to
be a part of that. I don't love the
circumstances of which I played. Um but
to help him through that to help him
kind of navigate that all was important.
Um because at at some point in time we
all get banged up. we all get hurt and
that mindset can can be wearing on you
and it can be tough and um the more that
we could see him be just uplifted about
being at practice, being around the guys
um was cool and I could really see kind
of all those things manifesting into
something great for him and he he
believes it. We all believe in him and
the more that we can continue to breathe
that confidence into him um I really
believe the sky's is the limit.
Thank you and congratulations again.
>> Thank you so much. I appreciate it. Good
to see you.
>> Ben.
>> Hey Marcus. Welcome back.
>> Thank you.
>> Um I guess just to go, you know, you you
talked about David Blau. How s when did
you find out that Cliff wasn't coming
back and how surprised were you
ultimately knowing how much you would
find this for the system that he wasn't
coming back?
>> Yeah, I learned uh early on in the
offseason. um you know and had
conversations and all those kinds of
things and just checking in and um yeah
it was tough. Um you know I I really
believe in Cliff. I believe in who he
is. Um I believe in the system that he
implements and um you know it was tough
to see him go and you know we had
conversations just catching up and
checking in and um you know he he's
somebody that I really look to as
somebody that I learned a lot from and
as a mentor and somebody that um I
developed a really good relationship
with. Um so I'm I'm excited to see where
he he goes. I'm excited to see how that
all pans out for him. Um, but like I
said, I learned a lot from him and I'm
grateful for the two years with him.
>> And just to uh with the free agency
situation, you said you explored it. How
surprising was it that the market got as
crowded as it did from where you were at
the end of the season to all of a sudden
a lot of known quarterbacks like
yourself were were going to be free
agents?
>> Yeah. Um, definitely an interesting free
agency I think for the quarterback
position. Um, you know, I was surprised
at kind of all that encompassed when we
got into free agency. Um, but like I
said, it it was humbling, you know, a
lot of the interest. Um, but also like
the situations, scenarios to me that
were presented never really felt right.
Um, this this feels right for me and
love to play, would love to get the
chance to go do it. Um, but I really
find this kind of mentor role really
rewarding. Um, and I'm I'm appreciative
of the fact that they wanted me back and
we'll see what it all looks like. Um,
but I'm excited to kind of navigate all
these new challenges together. And like
I said, I I love being in the
quarterback room with these guys and
excited to see what this all looks like.
>> Moyas.
Hey Marcus, congratulations. Just want
to start out by asking you, man, how
early do you get up to get dressed and
look so sharp in the morning?
>> No, I uh I just came off a red eye. So,
um you know, just got got changed in the
airport bathroom ready to roll. You
know, had this got the sweats on and
then got changed. Um we left I left
Portland about 11 o'clock last night and
then uh got in this morning around 6:45
and my flight back is like at 12. So,
trying to clean this all up, get going,
and and get back home.
>> Oh, a lot of the questions that uh
probably were going through my mind have
already been asked by some of my
colleagues, and I just wanted to get
your opinion on some of the moves the
Commanders have been make been making
this week. A lot of uh new faces coming
in, some uh strong players to support
this Washington Commander roster for
next season.
>> Yes, absolutely. And when it comes down
to it, I really believe in the core
group of guys that are here. um you know
Jay and LT um you know those cats have
already set the the foundation and the
culture. Um all these new guys that are
coming in um are going to love it and
they're going to love Q. They're going
to love the atmosphere that we've
created. Uh so regardless of who's
coming in, uh we're excited to to put
together this team. It always looks
different year to year. That's what
makes this this journey fun. And um I'm
excited to see how all this comes
together.
Thank you, Marcus. And uh good luck on
your way back.
>> Thank you. I appreciate it.
>> Awesome. Thanks, Marcus.
>> Thank you, guys. Take care. Nice to see
you. I'll see y'all soon.
>> Thank you.